(神楽)おい 聞いてんのか？
頭 ぶち抜かれたくなかったらな｡
ちょいと中 案内してもらおうか➡
(神楽)おい！ お前
この船の船員あるか？
Hey, are you a part of this ship's crew?
Could you show me around? Unless you want me make your head go pop.
Hey, you hear me?
[Shinsuke Takasugi leads the Kiheitai.
Bansai Kawakami, also known as Tsunpo.]
Crismon Bullet, Matako Kijima.]
[Shinsuke Takasugi leads the Kiheitai.
Scheming pervert, Henpeita Takechi.]
The butcher, Nizo Okada.]
["Be Careful Not to Leave Your Umbrella Somewhere"]
(高杉)今日はまた ずいぶんと
でけえ月が出てるな｡
There's a large moon out tonight.
(高杉)かぐや姫でも
降りてきそうな夜だと思ったが➡
I thought moon Princess Kaguya might come down tonight... But Princess Tomboy showed up instead.
[Note: refers to The Tale of Princess Kaguya.]
とんだ じゃじゃ馬姫が
降りてきたもんだ｡
《やばい…｡ ｺｲﾂ
やばいにおいが するｱﾙ》
This is bad. This guy smells dangerous.
(銃声)
(また子)うぉぉ！
(また子)ｷｻﾏ… 何者だ！
Damn you!! Who are you?!
晋助様を襲撃するとは
絶対 許さないっす！
I won't forgive anyone who threatens Shinsuke-sama!
銃を下ろせ！
Drop your gun! You think you can win against Matako Kijima quick-draw?
この 来島 また子の早撃ちに
勝てると思ってんすか!?
Matako, your panties are showing. I can see the stains.
[Note: Mata is slang for "crotch" in Japanese.]
また子 股見えてるよ
ｼﾐ付きﾊﾟﾝﾂが丸見えね｡
(また子)甘いな
注意をそらすつもりか｡
That won't work! Are you trying to distract me?!
Well, don't bother! I change it every day!
そんなん絶対ないもん！
毎日 取り替えてるもん!!
Yeah, yeah, but there really is something on it.
いやいや 付いてるよ｡
It's so disgusting.
きったねえな
また子の股は ｼﾐだらけ｡
Matako's panties are full of stains.
ｷｻﾏ!! これ以上 晋助様の前で
侮辱することは許さないっす！
Bitch! I won't forgive you for insulting me in front of Shinsuke-sama!
晋助様！ 違うんす
ﾎﾝﾄ 毎日 取り替えてますから➡
Shinsuke-sama! She's wrong. I really do change it daily!
確認してください これ…！
See for yourself, kore...
[Note: Konohamaru in Naruto often puts "kore" at the end of sentences.]
う… ｸｿｶﾞｷ！
You brat! Takechi Senpai, after her!
(また子)武市先輩 そっちっす！
(武市)皆さん
殺してはいけませんよ｡
Everyone, don't kill her.
Killing women and children...
(武市)女子供を殺めたとあっては
侍の名が すたります｡
is unworthy of samurai. So capture her alive.
生かして捕らえるのですよ｡
Senpai! Get your Lolita complex under control!
先輩！
ﾛﾘｺﾝも たいがいにするっす！
She breaks in here, and you go soft on her?!
ここまで侵入されておきながら
なにを生ぬるいことを！
I don't have a Lolita complex. I'm a feminist.
ﾛﾘｺﾝじゃない ﾌｪﾐﾆｽﾄです｡
敵とはいえども
女性には優しく接するのが➡
Even if she's the enemy, I must be nice to women.
ﾌｪﾐ道というもの…｡
(浪士)うあっ！
That's the way of the feminist.
(浪士)ああっ！
(浪士)うわっ！
(浪士)なんだ この小娘！
What the hell kind of girl is she?!
(浪士)やたら強いぞ！
She's super strong!
Zura! Where are you?!
ﾂﾞﾗ～！ どこｱﾙか～!?
う… うあっ…！
You're here, aren't you?!
ここに いるんでしょう！
いたら返事をするｱﾙ！
If you're here, answer me!
あ…｡
Now!
(浪士)い 今だ！
Hold her down!
押さえつけ… う！
ふんぬぅ!!
Wait for me!
待ってろぉ！ 今いくぞ!!
I'm coming!
Wh-What a kid...
なんてｶﾞｷだ…｡
Oh, no!
あっ いかん！ 工場のほうに！
She's headed for the factory!
(銃声)
♪♪～
あ… なんだ？ ここ｡
What is this...?
ｿｲﾂを見ちゃあ
もう生かして帰せねえな｡
Now that you've seen it, we can't let you leave this place alive.
(銃声)
[ODD JOBS GIN]
[OTOSE SNACK HOUSE]
(お妙)あ 気がつきました？
よかったぁ｡
You're awake, aren't you? That's a relief.
(お妙)全然 動かないから➡
You weren't moving at all, so I thought you might be dead.
このまま死んじゃうのかしらって
思ったのよ｡
大丈夫ですか？
意識しっかりしてます？
How do you feel? Are you conscious?
私のこと わかります？
Do you recognize me?
(銀時)まな板みたいな胸した
女… でしょう？
You're that woman with the chest like a chopping board, right?
(殴打音)
Why are you here?
お前… なんで ここに いるの？
Because Shin-chan asked me to take care of you.
(お妙)新ちゃんに頼まれたんです
看病してあげて って｡
なんで看病する人が
なぎなた持ってんの!?
So why is the person who's supposed to be taking care of me holding a Naginata then?
[Note: The Naginata is a traditional Japanese pole arm commonly wielded by women of the samurai class.]
新ちゃんに頼まれたんです｡
絶対安静にさせて➡
Because Shin-chan asked me to.
He said to keep you in bed and stop you from going out.
出かけようとしたら
止めてくれ って｡
止めるって何？ 息の根!?
Stop what? Do you mean my breathing?
そういや 新八や神楽はどうした？
By the way, where is Shinpachi and Kagura?
(お妙)あの…
用事で ちょっと出てます｡
Well... They're out running errands.
用事って何よ？
いいから いいから｡
What kind of errands?
Now, now. The patient needs to rest.
ｹｶﾞ人は寝ててください
さっ ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣読みましょうね｡
Let's read JUMP.
Hey. You're hiding something...
おい！ お前 何か隠して…｡
I said, don't move.
動くなっつってんだろう｡
What are you going to do if your wound opens up again, bastard?!
傷口開いたら
どうすんだ この野郎！
What?!
(鉄矢)なんですと!!
では紅桜は その辻斬りの手に!?
The killer is using Benizakura for a Tsujigiri?
[Note: Tsujigiri refers to a person or the practice of killing innocent people randomly in order to test a new sword or skill.]
(新八)すみません… なんとか
取り戻そうとしたんですが｡
I'm sorry. We tried to get it back, but...
(鉄矢)それで取り戻すことは
できたんですか!?
And did you get it?
No, I just told you we failed...
いや だから できなかったって
言ってるじゃないですか｡
That's terrible! The Benizakura has become an instrument of murder!!
なんてことだ！
紅桜が人斬りの道具に!!
This is way beyond the "this is bad" level!
(鉄子)…で 無事なのか？
えっ？
So, is he all right?
Huh?
あの… あの人｡
Th-That guy.
あぁ 銀さん？
You mean Gin-san? Well, he's not dead, but...
まぁ 死んではいないですけど
結構… やばい感じで｡
He's not all right either...
(鉄子)
兄者 気分が悪い｡ 外すぞ｡
Brother, I don't feel well. Excuse me.
んっ！ おい鉄子 どうした？
気分でも悪いのか!?
Hey, what's wrong? Tetsuko? You aren't feeling well?
She just told you she wasn't feeling well.
だから 気分悪いって
言ってるでしょうが！
いや すみませんねぇ
なんか 空気が読めないﾔﾂでね！
I'm sorry! She's no good at reading the situation.
ｵﾒｴが いちばん読めてねえよ…｡
You're the one who isn't able to.
それより１つ
お伺いしたいことがあるんですが｡
Anyway, I have something to ask you.
That sword, the Benizakura... What is it?
あの紅桜って刀…｡
あれ いったい 何なんですか？
I heard it's a demon sword that brings misfortune.
不吉を呼ぶ妖刀と聞きましたが➡
But I think there's more to it than that...
とても
そんな なまやさしいものじゃ…｡
あれは 妖刀とか➡
I don't think it's really a demon sword or something mysterious, and it's...
そんな謎めいたものじゃなくて…
きっと｡
残念ながら 私も紅桜について➡
Unfortunately, I don't know much about the Benizakura, either.
それほど深く
知っているわけではない｡
何しろ 触れてはならぬものと
蔵の奥深く封じていたのでな｡
We were never allowed to touch it and it was sealed deep inside the warehouse.
だが 私は思う！
But I have a theory.
刀匠が 精魂込めて
打ちあげた刀には➡
A sword made by a master swordsmith who put his heart and soul
得体の知れぬ何かが
宿ることもあるのではないかと｡
into his work just might have a soul of it's own.
あれを見たまえ！
Look over there!
(鉄矢)屋根から落ちた雨だれが
同じ個所に落ち➡
The continuous drip from that roof has worn a hole in that stone!
石に穴を うがっている｡
(鉄矢)雨でさえ岩を削る！
Even drops of rain can penetrate stone.
これが 意思をもった
一流の職人の槌ならば どうなる？
What if a world-class swordsmith does the same thing;
(鉄矢)斬るという
一念のみを込め➡
forging the same spot with his hammer?!
What if they pounded the iron tens of thousands of times with only the intent of forging a killing weapon?!
何百回 何万回も
槌を振り下ろされた➡
鉄ならば どうなる？
A sword like that might be beyond human understanding!
常識という名の薄い岩など
たやすく砕く刀！
そんなものが できあがっても
おかしくはないのではないか？
Would it be so strange if such a blade had a will of its own?
私は そう思う！
That's what I think!
つまり 親父さんの強い思いが
刀を 妖刀に変えたと？
You mean the strength of your father's will transformed cold steel into some kind of monster?
ﾜﾊﾊﾊｯ…！
Sounds like a romantic story, huh?
少々 ﾛﾏﾝﾁｯｸだったかな？
だが 刀匠の魂というのは
確かに打った刀に宿るものだ｡
But the spirits of master swordsmiths dwell in the blades they forge.
(鉄矢)斬る というたった一つの➡
The sword is forged with one deadly intention. To kill a person.
しかし 純粋な思いのもとに
作られてるからこそ➡
刀は あれほど美しい｡
That's what makes the sword so beautiful.
(鉄矢)そして
それを想像する職人もしかり｡
And so is the swordsmith who imagines it.
(鉄矢)刀も人間も
たった一つの目的に向かい➡
Whether it's a sword or a human being, beauty comes from striving towards a single goal!
進む姿は美しい！
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさん それって
もしかして桂さんの…｡
Elizabeth-san...
That's... Could that be Katsura-san's...?
[Don't say anything.]
神楽ちゃんが 帰ってこないんだ｡
Kagura-chan hasn't come back yet.
今朝 定春だけが
万事屋に帰ってて…｡
This morning, only Sadaharu came home...
こんな紙切れを… 雨に濡れて➡
...with this piece of paper.
It's a little wet and blurred, but it seems to be a map.
ところどころ見えないけど
地図みたいだ｡
銀さんには言ってない｡
I haven't told Gin-san about it.
そんなことを知ったら
あの人 あんなｹｶﾞしてるのに➡
If he knew she was missing, he'd go after her, despite his injuries.
とび出していくに決まってる！
(お妙)おい どこ行くんだ？
ｱｲﾀﾀﾀ…！
Hey, where do you think you're going?
Ow, ow!
いや ちょっと ｵｼｯｺ｡
Well, I'm just going to pee.
(お妙)ここにしろ！ ここで!!
Do it in here! Right here!
It's not enough! Not enough!
足りない 足りない 足りない…｡
(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
何のご用で？
あの… あれ…｡
Can I help you?
...Um... Well...
あの 銀さんなら 今は…｡
ここにいるぜ！
Um...Gin-san is currently...
Over here.
おぅ 入れや!!
来ると思ってたぜ｡
Oh, come on in. I knew you were coming.
You really overdid it this time.
(武市)
こっぴどくやられたものですね｡
(武市)紅桜を勝手に持ち出し➡
You took the Benizakura without permission and ran back here with only one arm.
更に それほどの深手を負わされ
逃げ帰ってくるとは…｡
腹を切る覚悟はできていますよね
岡田さん｡
Are you ready to commit hari-kiri one handed? Okada-san.
片手を切り落とされても➡
I should get credit for bringing Benizakura back even though I lost an arm.
ｺｲﾂを持ち帰ってきた勤勉さを
評価してもらいたいもんだよ｡
You should rethink my diligence in a situation like that.
ｺｲﾂにも いい経験になったと
思うんだがねえ｡
I think it was a valuable learning experience.
ｱﾝﾀの最近の身勝手ぶりは
目にあまるものがあるっす｡
Your selfish behavior the past few days has been too much.
What are you going to do if the Bakufu government's dogs find out about the Benizakura?
幕府の犬に
紅桜の存在を知られたら➡
どうするつもりっすか｡
You're distracting Shinsuke-sama.
ｱﾝﾀ 晋助様のｼﾞｬﾏなんすよ！
First Katsura and now Gintoki Sakata?
しかも 桂の次は 坂田 銀時？
晋助様を
刺激するようなﾔﾂばかり狙って➡
You're angering Shinsuke-sama by targeting those people.
いったい なに考えてんすか！
What were you thinking, anyway?
ｱﾝﾀ 自分が
強くなったとでも 思ってんすか？
You think you've become a big man? Don't delude yourself!
勘違いするんじゃないよ｡
ｱﾝﾀが
桂に勝てたのは すべて紅桜の…｡
You only defeated Katsura because of the Benizakura...
うぅっ！
Oh, it's nothing personal...
おっと 悪く思わないでくれ｡
It's been taking over my body more and more these days.
最近は すっかり
侵食が進んでいるようでね｡
もう ｵﾚの体を
自分のものと思ってるらしい｡
So it thinks my body is a part of itself.
ｵﾚへの言動は
気をつけたほうがいい｡
You'd better be careful how you talk to me.
本当のこと
話に来てくれたんだろう？
You came here to tell me the truth, didn't you?
この期に及んで➡
At this stage of the game, don't delude us into thinking it's a demon sword.
妖刀なんて言い方で
ごまかすなんてのはなしだぜ｡
ありゃ なんだ？
What is it?
Who really made that monstrosity?
誰が作った？ あんなﾊﾞｹﾓﾝ｡
岡田さん あなた…｡
(また子の咳込み)
Okada-san, you...
They're really bothersome.
どうにもｼﾞｬﾏでねぇ｡
ｵﾚたちぁ あの人と
この腐った国で➡
We've gathered here under him to overthrow this corrupt government.
ひと暴れしてやろうと
集まった輩だ｡
いわば 伝説になろうと
してるわけじゃないか｡
We are, so to speak, trying to become legends.
それを いつまでも
後ろで ｷﾗｷﾗとねぇ｡
But we're still just Kira kira...
[Note: Possibly a reference to Kira Kozukenosuke, the lord who was the target of the 47 ronin of Ako.]
(似蔵)目障りなんだ！
ｼﾞｬﾏなんだよ ﾔﾂら…｡
It's an eyesore. A real thorn in our side.
(似蔵)そろそろ
古い伝説には朽ちてもらって➡
Isn't it time for the old legends to die and the new legends to rise up?
その上に新しい伝説を
打ち立てるときじゃないかい？
(似蔵)あの人の隣にいるのは
もうﾔﾂらじゃない｡
They're not the ones at his side anymore.
(似蔵)ｵﾚたちなんだ｡
We are.
紅桜とは 私の父が打った紅桜を
雛形に作られた➡
The Benizakura was created based on my father's original Benizakura.
対戦艦用からくり機動兵器｡
It's a mechanized anti-battleship weapon.
Endowed with a kind of artificial intelligence called an "Electric Soul."
(鉄子)電魄と呼ばれる
人工知能を有し➡
使用者に寄生することで
その体をも操る｡
It lives like a parasite and takes over its wielder's body.
(鉄子)戦闘の経緯をﾃﾞｰﾀ化し
学習を積むことで➡
It even has the ability to record battles, analyze them and grow smarter.
その能力を向上させていく
まさに 生きた刀｡
It truly is alive.
(鉄子)あんなもんを作れるのは
江戸には一人しかいない｡
Only one person in Edo could create such a thing.
(鉄子)頼む… 兄者を止めてくれ｡
Please.
Stop my brother.
(鉄子)連中は… 高杉は…➡
They're...Takasugi is...going to use it to turn Edo into a sea of flames.
あれを使って
江戸を火の海にするつもりなんだ｡
♪♪～
Such insanity.
酔狂な話じゃねえか｡
大砲 ぶっ放して
ﾄﾞﾝﾊﾟﾁ やる時代に➡
To create a sword like this in an era of firearms and cannons.
こんな刀 作るとは…｡
I think a man who boasts about overthrowing the Bakufu
(鉄矢)ｿｲﾂで
幕府を 転覆するなどと➡
大ぼら吹く 貴殿も
十分 酔狂と思うがな！
with that sword is also insane.
A man who turns his boasts into reality is called a hero.
(高杉)ほらを実現してみせる
ほら吹きが➡
英傑 と呼ばれるのさ｡
I don't boast about what I can't do.
(高杉)ｵﾚは できねえ ほらは
吹かねえ｡
You truly are the son of the one-of-a-kind swordsmith, Jintetsu Murata.
しかし さすがは 稀代の刀工
村田 仁鉄の 一人息子…｡
It's unbelievable that you created something like this.
まさか こんな代物を
作り出しちまうとは…➡
鳶が 鷹を産む とは
聞いたことがあるが➡
I've heard of a black hen laying a white egg, but in your case, it goes beyond that.
鷹が 龍を産んだか…｡
侍も 剣も まだまだ
滅んじゃいねえってことを➡
Let's show them that the samurai and sword are far from extinct.
見せてやろうじゃねえか｡
(鉄矢)貴殿らが 何を企み➡
I'm not interested in your plots or ambition!
何を 成そうとしているかなど
興味は ない！
A swordsmith lives only to forge killing swords!
刀匠は ただ
斬れる刀を 作るのみ！
The only thing I can say is...
私に言えることは ただ１つ｡
There's nothing this sword can't cut!
この剣に 斬れぬものは ない！
(雨音)
高杉 晋助｡ その人が➡
Shinsuke Takasugi. Are you saying he's
桂さん失踪と
岡田 似蔵に関わる重要人物だと？
the major figure behind Katsura-san's disappearance and Nizo Okada?
While we were looking for Katsura-san, we followed many leads, but...
(志士)ｵﾚたちも
桂さんを捜す かたわら➡
いろいろ調べたんだが
まさかね…｡
ｵﾚたちと同じ
攘夷志士の仕業だったとは…｡
...we never thought we'd find another exclusionist rebel behind his disappearance.
And speaking of Shinsuke Takasugi, he was Katsura-san's old ally,
(志士)それに
高杉 晋助といやあ➡
かつて 桂さんとともに
攘夷戦争を戦った盟友だ｡
and they fought in the Anti-Foreigner War together. So why would he...?
ｿｲﾂが なんで…｡
According to rumors, Takasugi revived the Kiheitai
(志士)ｳﾜｻじゃ 高杉は
人斬り似蔵の他に➡
along with Nizo the Butcher; the gun fighter Matako "Crimson Bullet" Kijima;
紅い弾丸 と恐れられる 拳銃使い
来島 また子｡
that scheming pervert Henpeita Takechi; and the feared swordsman, Bansai Kawakami.
変人謀略家 武市 変平太｡
そして 似蔵と同じく
人斬りと恐れられる剣豪➡
河上 万斎らを中心に➡
鬼兵隊を 復活させたと
聞いたが…｡
The Kiheitai?
鬼兵隊？
(志士)かつて➡
It's a volunteer army led by Takasugi.
高杉が率いていた 義勇軍さ｡
文字どおり➡
It's said they fight like ferocious demons.
鬼のように 強かった って
話だが…｡
(志士)連中は 秘密裏に➡
I also heard that they're secretly developing devastating weapons.
強力な兵器を
開発しているとも聞く｡
His goal is to most likely form a strong-armed group to launch a coup d'état.
強力な 武装集団を作り➡
ｸｰﾃﾞﾀｰを 起こすのが
おそらく ﾔﾂの狙い｡
(志士)桂さんは 最近では
武力による攘夷を捨てて➡
Katsura-san renounced violence
and seeks to restore Edo's sovereignty by more peaceful means.
別の道を 探しておられた｡
Maybe Takasugi was angry with him for his change of heart.
袂を わかった かつての仲間に
いらだちでも➡
感じていたのだろうか？
高杉は…｡
なんにせよ このまま
黙って 見てるわけにはいかん！
Anyway, we have to do something!
Elizabeth-san, let's attack Takasugi's hideout!!
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさん！ 高杉のところへ
乗り込みましょう!!
Let's avenge Katsura-san!
[Calm down.]
[Note: The character "mo" is crossed out. Thus, it originally said mochitsuke, meaning "Pound mochi."]
(志士)桂さんの仇を！
(志士)高杉の首を 取りに!!
Take Takasugi's head!
なるほどね… 高杉が…｡
I see. Takasugi...
I don't know much about the situation,
事情は知らんが ｵﾒｴの兄ちゃん➡
とんでもねえことに
関わってるらしいな？
but it sounds like your brother is involved in a hell of a mess.
And... I can say that your brother used me like a pawn.
で？
ｵﾚは さしずめ その兄ちゃんに➡
ﾀﾞｼに 使われちまったわけだ｡
He asked me to look for a demon sword because he intended it to drink my blood.
妖刀を探せってのも
要は その妖刀に➡
ｵﾚの血を
吸わせるためだったんだろう？
Or he was asked by Nizo, who carries a grudge against me... Or maybe it was both.
それとも ｵﾚに恨みをもつ似蔵に
頼まれたのか…｡
いやぁ… その両方か｡
Either way, it's bad. And you knew it all along, didn't you?
にしても ひでえ話じゃねえか｡
お前 全部 知ってたんだろう？
兄ちゃんの目的を知ったうえで
黙ってたんだろう？
You knew your brother's plan, and yet you said nothing.
And now you're asking me to save him?
それで 今さら 兄ちゃんを
なんとかしてくれって…｡
Your skin is as thick as the monthly Shonen JUMP.
[Note: The monthly JUMP is thicker than the weekly JUMP. He's asking if she has thick skin.]
お前のﾂﾗの皮は 『月刊少年ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ』？
…すまん｡ 返す言葉も ない｡
I'm sorry. I have nothing to say.
Like you said, I knew everything...
ｱﾝﾀの言うとおり
全部 知ってた…｡
But I didn't tell you because I didn't want the truth to get out...
だが… 事が 露見すれば
兄者は ただでは済まないと…｡
that my brother was involved.
今まで… 誰にも言えんかった…｡
You sound like the little sister who's just trying to protect her brother.
たいそう 兄思いの妹だね…｡
Aren't you ignoring the fact that your brother is an accomplice to murder?
兄貴が
人殺しに 加担してるってのに➡
見て見ぬﾌﾘかい？
銀さん！
Gin-san!
刀なんぞは
しょせん 人斬り包丁だ…｡
After all, swords are made for killing people.
No matter how much heart and soul you put into its creation, you can't choose its user.
どんなに 精魂込めて打とうが
使う相手は 選べん｡
死んだ父が よく言ってた…｡
My dead father always said that.
His words are ingrained in our minds.
私たちの体に
染みついている言葉だ…｡
My brother is an idiot who only cares about making swords.
(鉄子)兄者は
刀を作ることしか頭にない ﾊﾞｶだ｡
He wanted to surpass our father, so he was always pounding iron.
父を越えようと
いつも必死に 鉄を打ってた｡
Soon after, he started researching machinery to gain greater power.
やがて より大きな力を求めて
からくりまで 研究しだした｡
That was around the same time he begun associating with shady people.
妙な連中と つきあい出したのは
その頃だ…｡
I was vaguely aware that they were bad people, but I didn't stop him.
連中が よからぬ輩だということは
うすうす 感づいていたが➡
私は 止めなかった…｡
I told myself that all we needed to do was just forge swords.
(鉄子)私たちは 何も考えずに
刀を打っていればいい｡
That's our job...
それが
私たちの仕事なんだ って…｡
(鉄子)わかってんだ…
人斬り包丁だって…｡
I knew it. A sword is for butchering people.
It was just a tool for murder.
あんなものは
ただの 人殺しの道具だって…➡
I knew...
わかってんだ…｡
Yet... What a shame...
なのに… 悔しくて しかたない…｡
(鉄子)兄者が 必死に作った
あの刀を…➡
My brother worked so hard to make that sword...
And it's being used for such a low purpose.
あんなことに使われるのは
悔しくて しかたない…｡
(鉄子)でも もう
事は 私１人じゃ➡
But things are reaching the point where I can't stop it on my own.
止められないところまで
来てしまった…｡
I really don't know what to do.
どうしていいか
わからないんだ…｡
What should I do?
私は どうすれば…｡
はぁ～｡ どうしていいか
わからんのは ｵﾚのほうだよ｡
I don't know what to do anymore than you do.
I'm wounded really badly.
こっちは こんなｹｶﾞはするわ➡
連れが やられて
頭ん中 ｸﾞﾁｬｸﾞﾁｬなんだよ｡
And my friend got taken out, too. So I'm not at my best right now.
Here! I don't want your consolation money. Just go home.
ほれっ！
こんな慰謝料も いらねえからよ➡
さっさと 帰ってくれや｡
もう 面倒臭せえのは
ごめんなんだよ｡
I don't want any more trouble.
♪♪～
《銀さんが 動けない今
ﾎﾞｸが 行くしかない…｡
Since Gin-san is out of action, it's up to me.
間違いなく 神楽ちゃんは
あの船にいる｡
There's no doubt that Kagura-chan is on that ship.
But how can I sneak aboard?
でも どうやって 忍び込む？
This place is crawling with scary looking ronin. What should I do...?
なんか 浪人が ｳﾖｳﾖしてるし
怖そうな人ばっかだよ｡
どうしよう…｡
あっ… なんか変なのいるぅ！》
What the hell is that?!
(また子)ｵｴｯ｡
いったぁ… ｸｯｿｰ｡
Ow... That bastard, Nizo. He's really out of control.
似蔵のﾔﾂめ 調子に乗りやがって｡
《また子:あの剣…
ﾎﾝﾄに大丈夫なんだろうか｡
I wonder if that sword is even safe to use. I could feel the evil in it.
なんだか とても
危険なものに感じたけど》
(浪士)うぉぉぉっ｡
(神楽)離すね！
Let me go!
Don't think you'll get away with this!
私に こんなことして➡
ﾀﾀﾞですむと思ってるｱﾙか!!
Don't come crying to me when you're beaten up by Gin-chan!
お前ら みんな！ 銀ちゃんに➡
ﾎﾞｺﾎﾞｺにされても知らないかんな!!
ﾊｧ… もう ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛなんすけど｡
Geez. She's already wreaking havoc.
だから さっさと 始末
しようって言ったんすよ｡
That's why I told you we should get rid of her.
ｶﾞｷ１人に なんすか この
ていたらくは… 武市先輩｡
Look at what this brat has done to our men, Takechi-senpai!
(武市)なんの情報も
つかんでいないのに➡
We can't kill her yet. She has valuable information.
殺してどうするんですか？
Besides, a girl her age will be in her prime in a few years.
(武市)それにね…
この年頃の娘は➡
あと２～３年したら 一番 輝く｡
ﾛﾘｺﾝも大概にして
くださいよ 先輩…｡
Your Lolita complex is showing again, Senpai.
I don't have a Lolita complex. I'm a feminist.
ﾛﾘｺﾝじゃありません ﾌｪﾐﾆｽﾄです｡
(武市)見てください｡
Look! Her gunshot wound has already healed in just one night
(武市)一夜にして あなたに
撃たれた傷が ふさがってるし➡
and her extraordinary strength and snow white skin...
それに あの尋常ならざる 強力｡
(武市)そして あの白い肌…｡
Senpai, please cut it out.
先輩 いいかげんにしてください｡
だから ｵﾒｴ違うって！
No, don't misjudge me. I'm a feminist with a healthy affection for children.
ﾌｪﾐﾆｽﾄだって言ってんじゃん｡
ただの子供好きの…｡
だから それ➡
That's someone who has a Lolita complex!
ただのﾛﾘｺﾝじゃないっすかぁ！
Never mind.
もういいですよ… あなたには➡
I don't think you understand, idiot.
理解できそうもないから ﾊﾞｶが…｡
ｵﾒｴが ﾊﾞｶ｡
You're the idiot.
あれですよ… 私が言ってるのは➡
I'm saying those characteristics are prevalent among the Yato clan.
これは 夜兎の
特徴と一致している➡
ということですしね｡
ｵﾏｴが死ね｡
You should die.
Yato... Is that the mercenary clan, Yato?
夜兎って… あの
傭兵部族 夜兎っすか｡
Does that mean she's a professional assassin who was hired to kill Shinsuke-sama?
晋助様を狙って 雇われた
ﾌﾟﾛの殺し屋ってわけっすか｡
Who the hell is she a spy for?
いったい どこの回しもんっすか｡
それが
何を聞いてもﾂﾞﾗしか言わないﾂﾞﾗ…｡
Well, no matter what we asked, she kept saying "zura, zura."
Senpai, she's mocking you.
(また子)先輩 それ
ﾅﾒられてんすよ…｡
ﾌｪﾐだかﾛﾘだか知んないすけど➡
I don't care whether you're a feminist or have a Lolita complex.
ｷﾓｲっすって ﾏｼﾞで｡
It's really disgusting. I'll show you how easily I handle this girl.
見ててくださいよ…
こんな小娘 ひとひねりで｡
Hey,
やい ﾃﾒｴ…｡
(神楽)ﾍﾟｯ｡
...you...
(また子)ﾃﾒｴ！
You!
Do you understand your situation?! I'll kill you!
自分の立場 わかってんすかぁ！
(また子)殺してやる!!
(武市)ﾀﾞﾒだって あと➡
N-No! This girl will be breathtaking in another two or three years.
２～３年したら すんごい
ことになるって この子…｡
Don't stop me, Takechi-hentai!
止めないでください！ 武市変態!!
(武市)先輩だから
変態じゃないから｡
I'm your Senpai, not Hentai!
(浪士)ｵｲｯ なんだ ｷｻﾏ！
(浪士)怪しいﾔﾂめ…｡
Hey, who are you, anyway?
You look really suspicious.
こんな 怪しいﾔﾂは
生まれて初めて見るぞ｡
You're the most suspicious person I've ever seen in my life!
You look like the ideal picture of a suspicious person.
怪しいﾔﾂを絵に描いたようなﾔﾂだ｡
《ちょ… 何やってんの あの人｡
Whoa! What is that person doing?! Oops, she's not human.
あっ 人じゃなかった
危ない！ やられる!!》
Be careful! She's going to get killed!
[Excuse me. Would you give me some directions?]
♪♪～
[To the entrance of Hell!!]
ｶｧｧｯ ｺｫｫｫｯ｡
ｶｰ ｺｫｫｫｯ｡
体じゅうのﾀﾝよ ｵﾗに力を｡
汚いから やめなさい｡
Phlegm throughout my body, give me strength!
It's so disgusting. Hey, please stop it!
Loogie!!
た～んじる…｡
ｺﾗｯ！
《神楽/また子:くらえ！》
(爆発音)
Eat this!!
♪♪～
What?!
(また子)なに!?
(神楽)なんだ!?
What?!
What do you mean "what?!" You spit all over my face.
なに じゃねえよ 人の顔
ﾀﾝまみれに しといて…｡
Hey, why are you only cleaning off my phlegm?!
ちょっ… なんで 私の
ﾀﾝしか拭かないんすか｡
右の頬に ﾀﾝつけられたら➡
It's said, "If you get phlegm on your right cheek,
左の頬にもって言うじゃないすか｡
you should get it on your left cheek, too!"
(２人)うわぁ あ…｡
♪♪～
What are you doing?!
(浪士)何してんだ ﾃﾒｴ！
曲者ぉぉ！ 曲者だぁぁ!!
An intruder! Intruder!
《ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…》
Elizabeth...!
♪♪～
[Hurry, go now!]
Elizabeth Senpai!
《ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ先輩！》
(お妙)安心しました｡
あ？
I'm relieved.
行くんじゃないかと思ったから｡
I was afraid you'd try to go out despite your injuries.
そんな体でも…｡
ﾌﾝｯ｡
…そんな体で行っても
死んじゃいますもんね｡
You'd die if you went out in your condition.
そうだな…｡
You're right.
(お妙)あの女の子には 申し訳
ないけど しかたないですよね｡
I feel sorry for that girl, but it can't be helped.
...You're right.
…そうだな｡
銀さん｡
あ？
Gin-san.
あんまり ﾑﾁｬをするのは
もう やめてくださいね…｡
Please don't overdo it.
銀さんが いなくなったら
新ちゃんも神楽ちゃんも➡
If you die, Shin-chan and Kagura-chan would be lost without you, Gin-san.
困りますから｡
…そうだな｡
...You're right.
Gin-san, you were pretty wild in your youth,
昔は 銀さんも
いろいろ やんちゃ➡
やってたようだけれども もう➡
but you've got to start acting your age now, you know?
そんなことする歳
じゃないですもんね｡
That's enough, damn it! I'm not going anywhere,
しつけえんだよ この野郎！
もう どこにも行かねえから
ちょっと ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣買ってこい！
so just go out and buy me JUMP!
お前 さっき
買ってきたの 赤ﾏﾙだぞ｡
The last one you bought was an Akamaru JUMP.
[Note: Akamaru JUMP is the special edition of JUMP.]
お母さんみてえな
間違いしてんじゃねえよ！
That's the kind of mistake my mom would make!
Yes, yes. I understand.
(お妙)はいはい わかりましたよ｡
♪♪～
…すまねえな｡
I'm sorry.
Watch it, moron!
(男)気をつけろ！ この野郎!!
♪♪～
[Wait at the swordsmith's. -Odd Jobs guy]
I hate to behave like an impulsive punk at my age, but....
ｵﾚだって いい歳
こいて やんちゃ➡
なんか やりたかねえ
けどよ… ん？ あっ｡
♪♪～
[This is my favorite umbrella. Please bring it back to me in one piece.]
Tsk... Troublesome woman...
ﾁｯ… かわいくねえ女｡
♪♪～
(お妙)ﾊﾞｶな人…｡
Stupid man...
[THE ANTI-Foreigner FACTION UPRISING]
[A VIOLENT CLASH BETWEEN]
[TWO LARGE FORCES.]
[BENIZAKURA'S...]
[POWER!]
[The next episode... "The Sun Will Rise Again"]
[After the Benizakura takes over part of Nizo, it'll become a monster.]
[Takasugi's beast continues to cry. Hurry up, Gintoki. Before everything is destroyed.]